# **Muhammad** Abbas

## CS Junior at Habib University

Competitve Programming Enthusiast & Flutter Application Developer



abbastaqvi81@gmail.com



smabbasht



923085685919



li-abbastaqvi

#### STATEMENT OF PURPOSE

I am a Computer Science Junior who is proficient with Git, GitHub and GitHub Desktop. I have switched to Linux 6 months ago and I am very much comfortable and proficient with terminal, therefore I'll enjoy assisting my fellow peers on Git CLI, I have been using Windows since my childhood so I am also fluent with GitHub Desktop. I have been managing my projects over GitHub for more than two years and I deeply understand the git operations and functions. I try to keep myself up-to-date with the new features and I have always been a curious guy regarding the tools, languages and software I use therefore, I end up getting so much comfortable with them, exploring the prolific features they offer.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## OFFICE OF INSTITUTIONAL RESEARCH AT HABIB UNIVERSITY DATA

INTERN

Aug 2021 - Sep 2021 | Karachi, Pak

- → Worked on Data Collection, Cleaning, Manipulation and Organization from confidential PDF files using NumPy, Pandas and Excel.
- → It was a two-month summer internship programme which entailed meeting with Dean and Program Directors, Data Collection, Cleaning, Manipulation and Organization, the model was later presented before the University President.

#### HABIB UNIVERSITY CS DEPARTMENT TEACHING ASSISTANT

Feb 2023 - May 2023 | Karachi, Pak

→ I am working as a Teaching Assistant for the course CS102: Data Structures and Algorithms.

#### **EDLAB PAKISTAN** DATA INTERN

Sep 2021 – Oct 2021 | Karachi, Pak

- → Learned Data Analysis using Power Bi and Excel.
- → Worked on Urban and Rural Educational Data Models.

#### **EDUCATION**

## HABIB UNIVERSITY BACHELOR'S OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Aug 2020 - Jul 2024 | Karachi, Pak

Related Courses Taken:

- → Data Structures and Algorithms
- → Data Structures II
- → OOP Design & Methodologies (C++)
- → Operating Systems
- → Artificial Intelligence
- → Operating Systems
- → Discrete Mathematics
- → Computer Architecture (Verilog & RISC-V)
- → Database Management Systems
- → Nature of Computation
- → Software Engineering

#### SKILLS

#### APP DEVELOPMENT

Cross-Platform App Development with Flutter and Firebase,

#### PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

Python (Expert), C/C++ (Proficient), Rust (Basic), JavaScript (Proficient), Dart (Proficient),

#### **TOOLS & SOFTWARE**

VCS: Git (Proficient), GitHub (Proficient), SVN (Basic)

**OS:** Linux (Proficient with Archlinux, Ubuntu, Fedora), Windows (Proficient)

**Other Tools:** HTML(Basic), CSS(Basic), La-TeX(Proficient), Markdown(Proficient),

#### **COMPETITIVE PROGRAMMING**

I have been doing Competitive Programming for more than two years.

LEETCODE - PROFILE CODEFORCES - PROFILE

#### **PORTFOLIO**

(Github Hyperlinks attached)

#### FRUIT NINJA GAME (C++ - OOP)

The Game was presented as Final Project of OOP and entails its all four pillars.

#### **EERTREE VISUALIZER (PY - DATA STRCTURES II)**

A Visualizer which constructs and displays Eertree(A Palindromic Data Structure) for any palindrome.

## CAR RENTAL SYSTEM (PY - DS & ALGO)

A Car rental System with Complete Admin and User Panels.

## T-REX GAME (VERILOG - DIGITAL LD)

A Game for physiopatients to keep them motivated during exercise.

#### **Flutter Projects:**

## INFAAQ PLATFORM (KHIDMAT)

An App that provides a platform for NGOs to post their cases & the donors can deposit the amount in the receivers account directly.

## FORGE YOUR WAY (IN PROGRESS)

An App focused on providing counseling to students looking for admissions in undergrad or graduate schools as well as to parents looking to enroll their students in schools.